# ROBERTO FLORES

## **Senior Software Engineer**

@ robertofloresdev0119@gmail.com

@ linkedin.com/in/robertoflores097

Prussel, Belgium

## **SUMMARY**

Professional software engineer with 10+ years of comprehensive experience in the Software Development industry. Provides strong technical direction across multiple projects. Experienced with the full software development lifecycle from planning to launch. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions, and global project management. A self-motivated, avid learner.

### **EDUCATION**

2010 - 2014

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science
 UCLouvain Saint-Louis Bruxelles

#### **EXPERIENCE**

01/2022 - 02/2024 •

Senior Software Engineer

London, UK

#### Quality IT

- · Mentored and provided technical guidance to an engineering team of 10+ members.
- Spearheaded the transition of online educational platform from LAMP stack to modern NextJS
   React Native-based architecture, resulting in a remarkable 300% increase of client company's revenue.
- · Implemented high-performance RESTful API endpoints using **Node.js** and **Nest** Framework.
- Designed **Postgres** database for microservices and optimized its performance by implementing advanced indexing strategies and query optimization.
- Led and participated in the development of various web and mobile applications including Renude, Relik, and Blockchef using cutting-edge technologies, including React, React Native, Next.js, Node.js, Golang, Python, and Laravel.
- · Actively contributed to code reviews, ensuring code quality, maintainability, and adherence to best practices.
- Strong background in cloud computing, including AWS, GCP, Docker and Kubernetes, proficient in designing and implementing cloud architectures, deploying and managing applications.

06/2019 - 12/2021

## Software Engineer

Denver, CO, USA

#### **Velocity Global**

- Served as one of the lead engineers in the development of Customer Experience Platform(CXP)-SaaS product of the company with a team of senior developers leveraging **React**, **NextJS**,
   **Golang**, **GraphQL**, **Docker**, and **AWS**.
- · Developed **RESTful** webservices and microservices using **Golang** for reading large volume of data from **Postgres** database.
- · Laid and designed architectural foundation of **GraphQL** layers for transport route optimization and billing automatization.
- Built a semi-auto mechanism which synchronously migrates CXP database into Glean data source using **React**, **Node**, **Python** and **Glean APIs**, resulting in a 30% improvement in speed and accuracy of data searching.
- Participated in the development of Document Management Platform(DOCX), providing AWS Lambda, FormKiQ and OPA solutions, and building high-performance RESTful APIs using TypeScript and NodeJS, handling an average of 1,000 large-scale requests per hour.
- · Collaborated with staff and principal engineers to provide proof of concept, **TDD**, and design and develop robust solutions to meet product requirements.
- · Mentored less experienced team members to follow the advanced development principles and methods.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### 06/2017 - 06/2019 •

#### Full Stack Developer

Brussel, Belgium

3E

- · Worked with a team of developers to migrate the existing UI from **AngularJS** to **React**, adding an extensive list of new features, unit tests and e2e tests for all features, key users, and roles.
- Led the end-to-end development process, including database design, frontend and back-end development, and AWS deployment, utilizing Node, React, React Native and MongoDB as the tech stack.
- · Overcame the challenge of limited payment integration options in Malaysia by conducting extensive research and selecting the best available service.
- Successfully delivered the MVP within a tight timeframe of just 6 months, ensuring its successful
  adoption by customers who are actively utilizing the platform's car and motorcycle lending
  services.
- Developed BOTs for car renting and property management services using Chatfuel, Facebook, and Dialogflow BOT frameworks for Facebook Messenger.
- · Worked on managing the **Git workflow**, reviewing the completed tasks and conducting the code reviews.

#### 07/2014 - 05/2017

## Front End Developer

Brussel, Belgium

#### **Adiutum**

- · Spearheaded the frontend development of ecommerce web applications using **React**, **Redux**, **Typescript**, **MUI**, **Bootstrap**, **SCSS**, etc.
- · Refactored the client-side of applications into a reliable **SPA** architecture.
- · Provided seamless user interface, kanban board, data visualizations, and designed overall user experience.
- Wrote high-quality code which covered 100+ unit and e2e tests to verify the functionality of UI components and overall workflow.
- Stayed updated with the latest **React** and **React Native** trends and libraries to enhance the app's competitive edge.
- · Provided powerful support to senior developers after becoming proficient in **React** and frontend technologies, resulting in a stronger, more efficient tech team.
- · Participated in the bootcamp sessions to learn and implement JavaScript and PHP framework basis.

#### **SKILLS**

Full Stack Development	Mobile App Development	Test Driven Development	Agile Development
DevOps			

#### CERTIFICATION

Full-Stack Web Development with React Front End Web Development Certification Certification

Back End Web Development Certification Free Code Camp Full Stack Development Certification

**Mobile App Development Certification**